<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book title="The Legions of the Serpent">
   <page>
      <title>Forming of the Serpent's Legions</title>
      <author>Komputa</author>
      <text>Long...Long Ago in a small rural village on the third continent, a wise magician married a talented alchemist.
	  They had a son, Elaphe Scalaris, who was prophesied to do great things.
	  While he was still a baby a very rare venomous snake bit the small child.
	  His parents worked quickly and created a magical antidote to heal their child. 

Many years later when Elaphe was an adolescent, their family was in deep debt to the evil lord of their land.
When his troops came to collect their payment, they didn't have enough to give them.
So they took Elaphe to work for the lord until payment could be paid.
Elaphe was locked up in the dungeon and was there for a long time.
His family were never to see him again, as they could never pay the high interest laid out by the evil lord. 

After a year had past the lords magicians and sorcerers came and blind folded and bound Elaphe.
They took him deeper into the castles underground to a dark ritual room.
Unknown to the evil lord, his sorcerers where members of the most evil guilds, who sought domination over the entire world.
They used their dark ways to gain power and bring havoc and destruction across the lands.
So, they took Elaphe and placed on a large stone bed.
They covered him with serpent stones and got out every snake found in the world.
They made all the snakes bite him in hopes that with the serpent stones they would create the ultimate warrior to lead their armies. 

But all did not go as planned.
The antidote that Elaphe's parents had given him when he was a child was a permanent ant antidote for all snakes.
His body fought the poison and his body began to absorb the serpent stones.
A bright red light emanated from his body as it tried to deal with the built up magic in his system.
The sorcerers dropped their snakes on him and stepped back, not knowing what was happening.
Scales started to appear all over his body, and a second head grew, he was turned into the first Snake-human. 

With his new found strength he killed all the sorcerers in the lord’s castle and cast the lord from his land.
He built a new and prosperous kingdom helping all of his serfs and promoting knowledge in the entire third continent.
The Serpent sent out his best warriors to hunt down enemy guilds, and to ally with other guilds to build up their strength.
He appointed Komputa the 'Serpent King' of his powers and people, as this army swept across C1 and C2.
With him came Fullmetal_aj the brave, Magrass the valeant, Zilvador the knowledgable, Elf_Ninja the wise, GabberGandalf the healer and Orcinus the great. 

This group of indefeatble men and women set out and recruited fellow players to their side, forming the evergrowing forces of the Legions of the Serpent.
From then on, Komputa and his followers continued to worship the Almighty Serpent, even though his whereabouts today remain unknown.
And it was done. The Serpent once again had power across Eternal Lands.</text>
   </page>
</book>
