<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book title="For Love and Honor, Ode of the Warrior Maiden">
  <page>
     <title>For Love and Honor, Ode of the Warrior Maiden</title>
     <author>kalhan</author>
  </page>
  <page>
     <text>Aubreyaunna and Nathaniel fought the dreaded horde,
By the Riven Sea they played a game of Lady and Lord.
They chased white bunnies along the shore,
pretending them goblins and orcs at war.
He happily played the lord so strong,
but the lady she would not play for long.
She would fight goblins along with him
until the sunlight would start to dim.

And the years swept by as they always do.
The lessons of life they were forced to pursue.
He trained as a warrior with bow and blade,
and she the ways of a proper young maid.
But when the sun would begin to fall
She begged him to take her to the training hall
For a warrior in her heart she would always be
if only she could make them see.

The years continued to march swiftly by
Their love for each other they could not deny.
So together they stood in a holy place-
Him in his armor, her in white lace-
and vowed to love till death do them part
But both knew it was forever in their heart.
He now a lord and her now his wife
Side by side they would walk together in life

The goblin wars still ravaged the land.
The blood of innocents soaking the sand
To sit and do nothing he could not do
Or else his life would have no value.
But she would not be left behind
their lives so closely were entwined
So battle after battle they fought
Side by side against the onslaught.

But the Gods were against them or so it appeared
for the enemy's numbers were worse then they feared
The call came from Tirnym to come and be counted
for the final battle was about to be mounted
from the young to the old, every able-bodied man
came to lay down their lives to make a last stand
Nathaniel too came to answer the call
For he knew they must not let Tirnym fall.

And Aubreyaunna would not be denied
She also came to fight at his side.
With one last kiss they turned to the fight
and lay into the foe with all their might
As the battle raged on through the day
They became separated in the fray.
And as the fighting surged on by
She was wounded and knew she would die.

With the last of her strength and will
She searched for her only love until
there at her feet he lay dying in pain.
But his love for her in his eyes was plain
And holding his head to her breast
she treasured these moments more than the rest.
As he gazed up into her loving eyes
he started to speak, to her surprise

"Do you remember when we were young
and the white bunnies we did run among?
I'd have you run side by side with me
once more along the Riven Sea.
You've been my friend, my wife, my love
and I swear by all that is above.
That if an afterlife there be
I will spend it forever with thee."

Then smiling through her tears so bright
and holding him against her tight.
She whispered softly in his ear
that she too wished that they were near
the Riven Sea in the morning sun
once more along its shore to run.
She kissed his dying lips goodbye
And closed her eyes with a sigh.

But if you happen to ever be
walking down by the Riven Sea
on some sunny summer's day
you may hear as from far away
the sound of laughter and of joy;
the voices of a young girl and boy
chasing the bunnies of pure white
Pretending them, goblins, they would fight.</text>
  </page>
</book>