<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book title="Tale of the Transparent">
<page>
<title>Tale of the Transparent; part of The Dragon Legends</title>
<author>Orion</author>
</page>
<page>
<text>Centuries before the wars in the age of the dragons, stood alone the transparent dragon. He wrecked havoc wherever he went with no purpose but his own entertainment.
The day had come when the dwarf king Zaluy crossed paths with the dragon... The outcome was inevitable.

Zaluy was the king of the great city that stood in Naralik, governing over hundreds of dwarfs. Their main business in life was to mine jewels from the secret caves under the castle.
Zaluy was a good fellow, always wanting to help, and also a great magician. This was unusual for dwarves as they typically practice the skills of matter (harvesting and mining) and not magic.

That day was a dark one, the sky covered with clouds. In the heart of the king there was no fear, he didn't make any enemies. But the transparent dragon didn't need enemies in order to attack.
It started with thunder, but the sound of it did not come from the sky. It was a bear dropped from the great maws of the dragon, on top of some dwarven women harvesting vegetables. The bear hit the ground, smashing the bones of the laboring women, throwing flesh and dirt all over.

Zaluy the king was standing at the window at the time, and without a moment to hesitate, he ordered everyone into the walls of the castle. Enraged, the dragon clawed at the walls, but they were solid stone and he couldn't get in. He started blowing flames at the gates and the roof of the castle; they caught fire immediately. Fearing for the lives of his people, Zaluy called "After me!" and led his people to the mines.
"we can get out through the tunnel to the marsh" he said, and lit a torch. His soldiers did the same and followed along. Behind them were the children. The dwarves don't have a big difference between male and female; so for outsiders it's hard to notice who is who. And not only they resemble each other, but they have the same physical and mental characteristics, so they fight and mine together (and that is why no women went with the children).

"Oh no" the king cried.
"what is it sir?" asked Prince Tumai.
"The tunnel... it's blocked, we can't get out."
The tunnel was blocked by big boulders that had crashed in when the bear hit the ground. It was just luck... bad luck.
"Sir, what now?" asked Tumai with sweat running down his face.
"The only thing we can, my good prince. We die."
Smoke came in the tunnel fast and soon everyone was gasping for air and falling to the ground.

With his last breath, the king screamed a curse to the air, "With mud and bones, I curse you all, dragons of the sky. As my flesh burns in your flame it can not consume my bones or soul and I will come when the day is right to take my revenge at you. SO I SWEAR..."

And then silence.</text>
</page>
</book>