<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book title="Laws of the Lands of Lord Luxin">
   <page>
      <text>Let ye know, that as ye wish to be a citizen or visitor of these lands, by the grace of the Lord Luxin, there are laws ye must abide by.

Know ye, that before the bulk of the laws of the land, there are 6 golden rules.

Mind thy Tongue
Ye shall not use language improper, foul, insulting, or otherwise offensive to those who may hear.
Ye shall not shout meaninglessly, nor repetitively, whether thy intent is to annoy, disrupt, or for any other purpose

Respect thy Neighbor
Ye shall not harass, threaten, or reveal private information of another upon these lands.
Ye shall especially be aware of those new to these lands; assisting them and not acting in a deceitful manor
Ye shall not misrepresent thyself as someone else, living or not, nor assist others in such deception.
Ye shall not restrict the way to a resource or way of passage. If ye are asked to stand aside that another may pass, ye shall do so.

Respect the Channels
It is by the grace of the Gods that we may have 'Channels' through which we may speak with those afar. Ye shall respect this magic, and contain thyself to the conversation topics of the Channel

Discard with Care
Ye shall not litter the lands with thy refuse; if ye wish to pass along a large stock to another, ye shall collect it all in a single place.

Summon not in busy locales
While the dark arts of resurrection and summoning may be tolerated, ye shall not practice them in places of common gathering, such as near those people who operate services of storage.
Ye shall also refrain from the summoning of mighty beasts on the island of Isla Prima

Accept rulings of the Eternal Guardians
If ye may feel the rulings of the Guardians in error, ye shall not question them publicly. If ye wish to debate the issue, contact the Guardian in private. If ye be yet unsatisfied, ye shall privately contact their Lady Aislinn.


Know ye, these laws of the land are subject to change at any time as the Lord Luxin may so deem appropriate.</text>
   </page>
</book>
