<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book title="Code of Conduct">
	<page>
		<title>Code of Conduct</title>
		<author>The_Antiroot</author>
	</page>
	<page>
		<text>Members of SegV should assist other guild members and allies when possible.</text>
	</page>
	<page>		
		<text>Members of SegV should not abuse the previous code of conduct by being overly demanding.</text>
	</page>
	<page>
		<text>Members of SegV should not use language that is offensive, racist or slanderous in public areas, or on public channels.</text>
	</page>
	<page>
		<text>Members of SegV shall not bagjump, scam, steal or act dishonorably, with the exception of these actions being carried out on listed enemy players.</text>
	</page>
	<page>
		<text>Members of SegV shall remain civil with newbies, regardless of how stupid the questions are. Always try to help, we all were newbies once.</text>
	</page>
	<page>
		<text>Members of SegV shall only PK in self defense, in arranged matches or optionally if the opponent is listed as an enemy. The other exception to this rule is if it is to teach another player a lesson, and the PK'r takes full responsibility for returning all goods. There MUST be a valid reason to do this.</text>
	</page>
	<page>
		<text>Members of SegV are expected to maintain a civil attitude in all players within the game. If accusations are to be made against other players, make sure you are correct.</text>
	</page>
	<page>
		<text>Members of SegV shall strive to enhance the Eternal Lands community.</text>
	</page>
	<page>
		<text>Members of SegV shall check the SegV forums regularly, for guild news, and to be kept in the knowledge of allies and enemies.</text>
	</page>
	<page>
		<text>Members of SegV MUST inform the Custodian of the Dictatorship, a Lieutenant or post on the forums if they are going to be absent for a prolonged period.</text>
	</page>
	<page>
		<text>Members of SegV MUST make every attempt to find the owner of a bag. Bags become the property of the finder after 20 mins of actively trying to find their owner. No fee shall be asked for returning a bag, however if you are offered a reward you may accept it.</text>
	</page>
</book>


