<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book title="Excerpts From The Truescrolls">
   <page>
      <title>Excerpts From The Truescrolls</title>
      <author>Derin</author>
   </page>
   <page>
      <text>These are excerpts from the doctrine of the Church of the Overdeity, known as the Brotherhood of Bane.


What went before...

Before time, before matter, before energy, the great gods of chaos ruled the vast masses of pure oblivion. And there was nothing until... something stirred in the unseen edges. Out of the roars of the chaos gods a thought was born. That thought planted itself, with uttermost care, in the minds of the gods. From that thought... matter, energy and time was born and planted into the endless plains of nothingness. There it waited.
In eternity lies the bringer of all.
In eternity it all shall fall.
In eternity - hear the primal call.

What came...

The Lands formed around that thought, fed by its promise of a new world. The chaos gods slowly turned their eyes to the Lands, and so the first Cataclysmic War began - the Creation War. The one thought was ever-present and it evolved with the tide of events. The Chaos gods were without thoughts and when the first thought erupted in the minds of the Chaos gods they were no longer free. The chaos gods were infused into the lands for all eternity, so was the birth of the Eternal Lands. Thus ending the Creation War.
The primal echo roared the night.
The Chaos begun their flight.
All was trapped by the thought of might.

The Eternal Lands saw beings develop out of the first thought and the chaos of the gods. So came man, elf, dwarf and beast to ravage the Eternal Lands.

What was...

Out of chaos came order and the first thought was split into good and evil, so the second Cataclysmic War began - the Great War. In the Great War new empires saw their dawn, but there were also a seed of chaos emerging. Finally chaos erupted by the hand of Bane. Bane is greatest of all gods, the first god, the primal god - the creator of all. Bane saw the evil seed in the Eternal Lands grow stronger and stronger and out of that vision he saw what had to be done - evil had to be eradicated from the Eternal Lands. So the great bane of all evil formed a shimmering wave that swept across the continents, wiping the memories of all sentient beings.
The war was a howling hound.
Chaos to the thought was bound.
The Land deprived of sound.

Then he entrusted upon Aluwen to Awaken the sentient of the Eternal Lands, hoping that they would escape the curse of Mortos. Aluwen followed the biddings of the primal god, hoping that the new memories would tear the souls away from the dark curse that had fallen upon the dwellers of the lands. So came the returners to the Eternal Lands. Then they learned the true purpose of the curse of Mortos...

What is...

As a final act, the great god Bane infused some of his powers into the men that were to be the Divine Rulers of the Brotherhood of Bane. The Divine Rulers began their quest to bring goodness to the Eternal lands. The path of Light, the road to salvation, the breaking of the curse was their to find. They knew, in their minds, that only the complete vanquishing of all evilness would ever bring Bane back to the Eternal lands..

We wait, we uphold your decree.
Make eternity to us free.
The Path of light will return to thee.</text>
   </page>
</book>
