<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book title="Crystal Technology">
   <page>
      <title>Crystal Technology</title>
      <author>Sheesh, Orchan Alchemist of Morcraven Marsh</author>
      <text>
 Note: All information with a (*) denotes real information about real crystals and minerals. Any information that does not contain a (*) is fantasy based.
 
 All good alchemists are picky on the quality of the items they use, as a faulty raw ingredient  leads to a failed product.  Since the products we make often makes a difference between life and death, it is very important to know and understand the crystals you use to make the finished product. Here are my notes on the various crystals that will aid you here in Eternal Lands.
 </text>
 </page>
 <page>
 <text>
Amber*
Amber is not a true stone. It is fossilized resin of coniferous trees of the Oligoncene geological epoch, some thirty million years ago. It varies in color from pale yellow to dark brown, although some specimens have been found that are red. Amber is famous for containing insects and small animals of various kinds as well as leaves, bark and other contemporary detritus which became stuck and enclosed in the resin while it was still liquid. Amber has always been associated with magic. It is a favorite protective and enhancing stone of Wiccans and Shamans. It is a sensual, (amber is warm to the touch,) magnetic stone that attracts love. In ancient times, amber was burned to cleanse the air, especially during childbirth. It was also thought to improve eyesight by gazing into it.

Diamond*
Diamond is made from high pressure on carbon atoms.  It brings fierceness, strength and fortitude. Diamonds strengthen friendships and protects from evil, disease and plagues. If set in gold it drives away night monsters... When stolen attracts negative vibrations. Diamonds require cleaning often. The six sided luckiest square brings balance and harmony triangular disharmony and friction.

Emerald*
Emerald is a type of Beryl, Beryllium aluminum silicate, frequently with some sodium, lithium and cesium. It's chemistry is Be3Al2Si6O18. Beryls range in color from Bright green (emerald), blue, greenish blue (aquamarine), yellow (golden beryl), red, pink (morganite) to white. The streak is colorless. The crystals are Hexagonal and they are common. Fine emeralds have velvety body appearance; their value lies in their even distribution of color. Inclusions are common in emerald, but other stones of this group are usually most valuable when free of flaws. Beryl develops in pegmatites and certain metamorphic rocks. It occurs with quartz, microcline, and muscovite in pegmatites, and with quartz, muscovite, and almandine in schist of regional metamorphic rocks. It has come to represent, for many people, the security of love. Emerald, like almost all of the green stones, is also advantageous for business/money ventures. Emerald is said to aid perception and inner clarity. Because of this, they are also associated with healing diseases of the eye, and problems affecting eyesight. It was believed that emeralds could counteract poisons and cure disentary.

Gypsum*
Gypsum is a very soft mineral composed of calcium sulfate dihydrate, with the chemical formula CaSO4·2H2O. Gypsum occurs in nature as flattened and often twinned crystals and transparent cleavable masses called selenite. It may also occur silky and fibrous, in which case it is commonly called satin spar. Finally it may also be granular or quite compact. In hand-sized samples, it can be anywhere from transparent to opaque. A very fine-grained white or lightly-tinted variety of gypsum is called alabaster, which is prized for ornamental work of various sorts. In arid areas, gypsum can occur in a flower-like form typically opaque with embedded sand grains called desert rose. Uses for gypsum include cement, plaster, surgical casts, toothpaste, tofu, and dietary calcium additives.

Obsidian*
Obsidian occurs as volcanic lava flows that are thick and of limited area. Its black, glassy, lustrous, and often flow-banded appearance makes it rather easy to distinguish from the other volcanic rocks with which it is commonly associated. This mineral forms when a silica-rich magma of granitic composition flows onto the earth's surface, where it solidifies before minerals can develop and crystallize. It is, therefore, an amorphous solid or glass rather than an aggregate of minerals. Primitive peoples once valued obsidian highly, chipping and flaking it into knives, spearheads, and many other implements with razor-sharp edges resulting from the intersecting conchoidal fractures. Obsidian is a very protective stone. It is also associated with the inner mysteries of the Goddess, symbolizing entrance to the labyrinth,the womb or the subconscious self. Because of its protective qualities, Obsidian is a good stone for those who are soft-hearted and gentle. It will help to guard them against abuse. This stone cleanses toxins from the liver, so it is also good for people who are exposed to environmental pollutants.

Quartz*
Quartz is a hexagonal crystal structure made of trigonal crystallized silica (silicon dioxide, SiO2). Quartz is not one of the world's most common crustal minerals and goes by a bewildering array of different names. Although many of the varietal names historically arose from the colour of the mineral, current scientific naming schemes refer primarily to the microstructure of the mineral. Colour is a secondary identifier for the cryptocrystalline minerals, although it is a primary identifier for the macrocrystalline varieties. Quartz is a common constituent of granite, sandstone, limestone, and many other igneous, sedimentary, and metamorphic rocks. Clear quartz is Known as "Ice of Eternity." All-around healer and amplifier. Capable of dispersing white light into the seven spectral colors. Aligns one's consciousness with the electromagnetic forces of the universe, helping each of us find our own inner light that connects us with the One Light. Magnifiers of psychic and healing energies. Used to help focus and amplify one's thoughts or intentions.

Blue quartz*
Similar to regular quartz but light blue in colour. Blue quartz is a fine peace and tranquility stone that stimulates creativity and expression.

Rose quartz*
Rose quartz is a type of quartz which exhibits a pale pink to rose red hue. The color is usually considered as due to trace amounts of titanium, iron, or manganese, in the massive material. Rose quartz teaches one how to give and receive love and one the power of forgiveness. Rose quartz opens the heart allowing emotional release, heals soul trauma, clears and encourages a beautiful complexion. In addition, it also prevents wrinkles, helps one reduce weight, and works on the thymus gland. 

Sapphire*
Sapphire is a member of the Corundum family, along with ruby. Both are basically aluminum oxide. It's chemistry is Al2O3. All colors of Corundum are considered to be "sapphire" unless they are red (Ruby.) It ranges in color from pink, blue, green, violet, gray, yellow and many shades in between. The crystals are Hexagonal; sometimes tapering prismatic; also pyramidal, tabular. It is often striated. Sapphire has been associated with divine favor. Sapphire is considered an aid for developing the "third eye". It was also considered to be able to guard its owner from being captured. It is worn and utilized in rituals to strengthen the ability to tap and send forth power. Sapphire has been use as an aide to healing ailments of the eyes. It is also considered a booster for the immune system, protecting the body in general from disease.

Ruby*
Ruby is in the Corundum family, like sapphires. The only difference is the colour. Rubies aid regeneration of physical/spiritual heart. They enhances circulation, vitalizes blood and entire body/mind system and strengthens immunity. In addition, they activate sluggish or dormant conditions on physical/spiritual levels, refines lower passions, and aid in courage, integrity, selfless service, joy, spiritual devotion, power, leadership. Rubies help banish a sense of limitation. 

Turquoise*
Turquoise is a Hydrous basic phosphate of copper and aluminum. It may occasionally contain some iron. This mineral ranges from sky-blue through bluish green; even occasionally apple green. This stone has long been used for protection against traumatic injuries. It was thought that the stone would shatter, thus warning the wearer of imminent physical danger. It was also used to decorate the bridles of horses, to protect them against broken bones from falls. Turquoise is believed to be a connector of Earth and Sky.Turquoise is thought to increase Wisdom. It is recommended that healers wear Turquoise to increase theirpower. This stone is also said to heal the emotional "heart" of the individual. In addition it has been recommended for healing stomach disorders and for the eyes.</text>
 </page>
 </book>






